<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items</name>
		<description></description>
		<author></author>
		<update version="0.3.3">
			<file name="magic-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ThatDeltaGuy/Aurora-Custom/master/light-of-xaryxis/magic-items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

    <element name="Arcane Reflector" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCANE_REFLECTOR">
		<description>
			<p>This shield has a large, purple gemstone at its center. When you are the target of a spell of 1st level or higher that targets only you while carrying this shield, you can use your reaction to attempt to redirect the spell. Roll a d8. If the roll is higher than the spell’s level, the spell targets another creature of your choice you can see within 30 feet of you. If the roll is equal to or lower than the spell’s level, the spell isn’t redirected and the shield loses its magic as the stone in its center crumbles to dust.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Briefcase of Abnormalities" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_BRIEFCASE_OF_ABNORMALITIES">		
		<description>
			<p>This strange-looking, red, triangular briefcase is inscribed with various eldritch symbols. As an action, you can open the bag and pull out an object from the bag and throw it up to 20 feet. When the object lands, it transforms into a creature determined at random by rolling a d8 on the table below. The creature vanishes after 1 hour or when it is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
			<p>Flip a coin to decide if the creature is hostile or friendly to you and your companions. Whether friendly or not, it acts on its own initiative and in a fashion appropriate to its nature. Once an object has been pulled from the bag, the bag can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>

            <p>d8 Creature</p>
			<ol>
                <li>Flumph</li>
                <li>Psurlon Ringer</li>
                <li>Gibbering Mouther</li>
                <li>Intellect Devourer</li>
                <li>Spectator</li>
                <li>Feyr</li>
                <li>Otyugh</li>
                <li>Cloake</li>
            </ol>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Crossbow of Portals" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_CROSSBOW_OF_PORTALS">
		<description>
			<p>The crossbow has 4 charges. This intricate crossbow is coveted by high-profile Wildspace brigands. You can take an action to expend 1 charge from it to fire at a flat surface within 120 feet that is at least 10 feet tall and 10 feet wide to create a portal on that surface.</p>
			<p class="indent">The crossbow alternates between creating blue or red portals and glows the color of the portal it is ready to create. Any creature or object entering a blue portal exits from a red portal as if the two were adjacent to each other (and vice versa). A portal created by the crossbow lasts for 1 minute or until a new portal of the same color is created.</p>
            <p class="indent">The crossbow regains 1 expended charge every 8 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Crossbow, Hand">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CROSSBOWS_HAND</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Heartbreaker's Brooch" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_HEARTBREAKERS_BROOCH">
		<description>
			<p>While you’re wearing this brooch and make an ability check using Charisma, you can choose to gain advantage on the roll. Once this property has been used, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Beguiling Magic.</em></strong> This brooch has 3 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells (spell save DC 13): <em>charm person</em> (1 charge), <em>crown of madness</em> (2 charges), or <em>suggestion</em> (2 charges)</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Illithid’s Breastplate" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_ILLITHIDS_BREASTPLATE">
		<description>
			<p>This magical armor is made of steel on the outside and reinforced with a tough, carapace-like material on the inside. While wearing this armor, you have a +1 bonus to AC and can speak Deep Speech.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mind Blast.</em></strong>  As an action, you emit a blast of psychic energy. Each creature within 20 feet of you must succeed on a DC 13 Intelligence saving throw or take 18 (4d8) psychic damage and be stunned until the end of its next turn. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="breastplate">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="armor">Breastplate</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Potion of Wrath" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_POTION_OF_WRATH">		
		<description>
			<p>Bloodied veins seem to grow along the edges of this glass vial which contains a blue liquid brewed from the brain of a freyr mixed with the blood of a giant. For 1d4 hours after drinking the potion, you gain the following effects:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your hit point maximum increases by 10, and you gain the same number of hit points.</li>
				<li>You gain the “enlarge” effect of the enlarge/reduce spell (no concentration required).</li>
				<li>You’re immune to being frightened but have disadvantage on saving throws against being charmed.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>When the effect ends, hideous deformities appear on your skin, and you gain one level of exhaustion plus one additional level of exhaustion for each time you’ve previously drunk a potion of wrath within the last year. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Potion</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Psionic's Mitts" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_PSIONICS_MITTS">
		<description>
			<p>These magic gauntlets are powered by a gravity crystal. As an action while wearing the gauntlets, you can attempt to telekinetically move a Medium or smaller creature or an object weighing 10 pounds or less that you can see within 60 feet of you. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be moved up to 30 feet in any direction. If the target is an object, a creature wearing or carrying the object can make a DC 13 Strength (Athletics) check. If the creature succeeds on its check, the attempt fails. If the creature fails, or if the object isn’t being worn or carried, it is moved up to 30 feet in any direction.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Gravity Wave.</em></strong> As an action, you release a wave of gravitational energy in a 60-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 21 (6d6) force damage, and its speed becomes 0 until the end of its next turn. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Starseeker’s Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="Light of Xaryxis" id="ID_LOX_MAGIC_ITEM_STARSEEKERS_AMULET">
		<description>
			<p>This circular amulet is crafted from a strange black metal and has a depiction of a star at its center. While you’re attuned to a spelljamming helm and wearing this amulet, you have resistance to psychic damage. Additionally, you have advantage on Constitution checks made to resolve a spelljammer duel.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Jammer.</em></strong> As an action, you can target one spelljamming ship within 300 feet of you that you can see and attempt to magically suppress the properties of the ship’s spelljamming helm. If the ship has more than one helm aboard it, randomly determine which helm is affected. A creature attuned to that helm must make a DC 13 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 28 (8d6) psychic damage and the helm’s magic is suppressed for 1d10 minutes. On a successful save, you take the damage instead and the helm’s magic isn’t suppressed. Once used, this property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
